# Shivkumar M

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER

Over 8+ months of IT experience, including 5+ months of experience as a React JS Developer. Experience in developing web pages using HTML5, CSS3, React JS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JSON.

Email -mshivkumar59@gmail.com Location - Bengaluru, India Portfolio - https://shivkumar-portfolio-rho.vercel.app

+91 7624862659

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### <u>Assistant System Engineer</u>

Tata Consultancy Services

12/2021 - Present,

- Over 8+ months of IT experience, including 5+ months of experience as a React JS Developer.
- Experience in developing web pages using HTML5, CSS3, React JS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, and JSON.
- Experience using React JS components, Events, Forms, Router, and React Hooks.
- Knowledge in developing single-page applications (SPAs) with handling APIs with Axios.
- · Experience working with version control GIT

#### **CURRENT PROJECT**

Sony Liv (04/2022 - Present )

Sony Liv is an OTT platform where users can watch their favorite movies, shows, and sports with a premium subscription

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Engineering** 

Sampoorna Institute of Technology and Research 06/2017 - 08/2021, 7.3 - CGPA

COURSE

**Computer Science Engineering** 

### <u>SKILLS</u>



#### **ORGANIZATIONS**

#### **Tata Consultancy Services**

(7+ months) - present Software Developer Internship

#### **Techciti Technologies**

(2 months ) - 2019 Software Developer Internship

#### Shape AI

(2.5months) - 2020 Full Stack Web Developer Internship

#### LANGUAGES

- English
- Kannada
- Telugu

## **Projects Details**

### **Project Overview**

Project Name: Book My show -Clone

Organization - Shape AI

Book my show is an online platform where users can book their movie tickets online by selecting the theatre and selecting the seats and paying the fees for the selected seats accordingly. Users can pay the amount using "UPIs", "Credit / Debit Cards" or using "Net banking" and payment is completed using the "Razor Pay" payment gateway.

### **Roles & Responsibilities**

- Setup a new project page using React JS and install Tailwind CSS
- Build a responsive site that should fit each device
- Develop a page with sample pictures for the entire movie poster
- Style the page using Tailwind CSS with the exact colors used by Book my show
- when users click on a movie poster redirect to the movie details page using reactrouter-dom
- Remove the sample pictures and replace them with actual movie posters using "TMDB" movie database API using "Axios" and "useEffect" hooks
- Deploy the completed site into "vercel"

### **Project Overview**

Project Name: CoinsHub

The aim is to develop a crypto price tracker website. where users can see the day to day price of the crypto coins prices and make a section of a trending coins listed in home page using Coin-Gecko API to fetch the details of the coins listed in cryptocurrencies

### **Roles & Responsibilities**

- Setup a new project page using React JS and install Bootstrap
- Build a responsive site that should fit each device
- Develop a Home page with a Search bar, whenever the user search name it should redirect to the details page and show the coin details
- Style the page using Bootstrap and CSS
- Add carousel using "React Slick"
- Added navigation link where users can navigate to the next page using React-Router-DOM
- Fetched coins data and prices data using "Axios" from "Coin-Gecko" API
- Used simple area chart from reacting "Re-Charts"
- Deploy the completed site into "vercel"

### **Project Overview**

Project Name: Wynk -Clone

"Wynk music" is an online music player application where users can listen to their favorite music for free and users can get a premium subscription and listen to the add free music for the subscribed period. users can download this app from Play store or App store

### **Roles & Responsibilities**

- Setup a new project page using React JS and install Bootstrap
- Build a responsive site that should fit each device
- Develop a page with sample pictures for the entire music images
- Style the page using Bootstrap
- Add carousel using "React Slick"
- Added navigation link where users can navigate to another page using "react-router-dom"
- Remove the sample pictures and replace them with actual music posters using "TMDB" movie database API using "Axios" and "useEffect" hooks
- Deploy the completed site into "vercel"

### **Project Overview**

Project Name: Meme Generator

"Meme generator" is a fun application where users can generate memes using this application with simple steps providing two input fields to add text over an image and a random image button to fetch a meme image from API

### **Roles & Responsibilities**

- Setup a new project page using React JS
- Develop a page having 2 input fields, a button, and an image under the button
- Style the page using CSS
- Fetch meme images from API and add an event handler to a button when users click on the button it should generate a new image
- Add a function to form whenever the user enter a text in the input fields then the text should appear over the image.
- Build a responsive site that should fit each device
- Deploy the completed site into "vercel"